Finding Aid for Core Technology Alliance records, 2001-2008
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Core Technology Alliance records 2001-2008
Core Technology Alliance.
2013158 Bimu N202 2
The Core Technology Alliance was a collaborative network of advanced technology facilities established as a part of the Michigan Life Sciences Corridor to advance investment in biotechnology and business development in Michigan. The University of Michigan was one of the member institutions. The records date from 2001 to 2008 and are primarily made up of administrative files, reports and board of directors meeting minutes detailing the operation of the Alliance.
6 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was transferred by the Office of the Vice President for Research (Donor No. 5123 ) in July 2013 5123
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
The Core Technology Alliance (CTA), part of the Michigan Life Sciences Corridor, began in 2001 to serve as a catalyst for life sciences, biotechnology research, and business development. In order to advance life science research in the State of Michigan, the required cutting-edge technology would require more investment capacity than any single company or institution was capable of, thus the Alliance was formed. Its goals were to provide new and enhanced technology to life scientists in Michigan, create incentives to work with industries, foster an environment of collaboration amongst academic and corporate users, attract researchers to Michigan, and train a new generation of life science investigators.
The facilities that CTA developed were designed for use by researchers affiliated with universities, private research institutes, and biotechnology or pharmaceutical firms within Michigan. It served to coordinate the core facilities at the Van Andel Research Institute, Michigan State University, the University of Michigan, Wayne State University, Western Michigan University, Kalamazoo Valley Community College and Grand Valley State University. The facilities include the Michigan Animal Models Consortium (MAMC), Michigan Antibody Technology Center (MATC), Michigan Good Manufacturing Practices (MGMP), Michigan High Throughput Screening Center (MHTSC), Michigan Center for Bioscience Commercialization (MCBC), Michigan Center for Structural Biology (MCSB), Michigan Center for Biological Information (MCBI), Michigan Proteome Consortium (MPC), and Michigan Center for Genomic Technologies (MCGT). Start-up funding for the Core Technology Alliance was provided by the Michigan Life Sciences Corridor Initiative, later known as the Technology Tri-Corridor Initiative, and further funding was provided by the Michigan 21st Century Job Fund. However, the Alliance began struggling in its search for funding in 2008.
The Core Technology Alliance records date from 2001 to 2008 and are primarily made up of administrative files, reports and board of directors meeting minutes detailing the operation of the Alliance. The records date from 2001 to 2008 and contains three series: Administrative, Financial, and Meetings.
Subjects:
Biotechnology--Research--Michigan.; Core Technology Alliance.; Life sciences--Michigan.; Michigan Economic Development Corporation.; University of Michigan. Life Sciences Institute.; University of Michigan. Office of the Vice-President for Research.
- Administrative
  The Administrative series (2.5 linear feet) contains general information about the various branches of the Core Technology Alliance, the application for funding from 21st Century Jobs, reports and reviews, by-laws, grant applications, information on the relations with the Michigan Economic Development Corporation and the American Association for the Advancement of Science, and other administrative information.
  - 21st Century Jobs 2006, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Administrative Care Section Proposal 2006 (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) Report of CTA Review 2003 (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) Review 2004 (Box 1)
  - Articles of Incorporation By-Laws 2004 (Box 1)
  - Board Non-Voting Members 2004 (Box 1)
  - Center for Advancement of Clinical Research (CACR)-National Institutes of Health (NIH) Translational Research Planning Grant 2005, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Charter 2002-2003 (Box 1)
  - Contact Directory (Box 1)
  - Crain's Advertisement 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - Data Universal Numbering System (DUNS) Number 2004 (Box 1)
  - Deibel, Robert 2003-2004 (Box 1)
  - E-Newsletter 2001 (Box 1)
  - Employee Identification Number 2004 (Box 1)
  - General Information 2002 (Box 2)
  - Grant Proposal and Agreement with Michigan Economic Development Corporation (MEDC) 2004 (Box 2)
  - Letter of Support for Michigan High Throughput Screening Center (MHTSC) 2005 (Box 2)
  - Letter to President Lee Bollinger 2001 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Economic Development Corporation (MEDC) -- AAAS Site Visits 2003 (Box 2)
  - MEDC -- AAAS Site Visit 2004, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - MEDC for CTA Corporation 2007-2008, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Michigan Life Sciences Corridor (MLSC) Progress Report 2006 (Box 2)
  - Michigan Proteome Consortium (MPC) Budget Reallocation 2006 (Box 2)
  - MPC Press Release 2003 (Box 2)
  - Progress Report 2004, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Qoranfleh, M. Walid 2005-2006 (Box 2)
  - Research Funding for Dow Pharmaceutical Facility 2002-2003 (Box 2)
  - Retreat 2002 (Box 2)
  - Service Agreements 2002-2005, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Society of Research Administrators (Box 3)
  - Special Studies, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - State of Michigan Annual Report 2005 (Box 3)
  - Support Proposal Approval Form 2007 (Box 3)
  - Sustainability Projections for AAAS Review 2004, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Technology Transfer 2001 (Box 3)
  - Web Site Work Group 2001 (Box 3)
- Financial
  The Financial series (1 linear foot) contains summaries of accounts, budget and financial reports, financial agreements, and tax information.
  - Accounts Summary (Box 3)
  - Budget 2001-2006, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Financial Report 2005-2006, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - General 2002 (Box 3)
  - Office of the Vice President for Research (OVPR) Budget 2005-2006 (Box 3)
  - Plante and Moran Agreement 2005 (Box 3)
  - Tax Exemption Application 2004-2005 (Box 3)
  - Tax Returns 2004-2006, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Vendor Registration and Funds Transfer 2004 (Box 4)
  - Wired for Growth Insurance Policies 2004-2007, 2 folders (Box 4)
- Meetings
  The Meetings series (2.5 linear feet) primarily consists of minutes and schedules from Board of Director Meetings. Also included are minutes from meetings of the Executive Committee, the annual board meeting, and Facility Hub/Node meetings.
  - Annual Board Meeting 2006 (Box 4)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, 32 folders
    - March, 2004 (Box 4)
    - May-September, 2004 (Box 4)
    - November, 2004 (Box 4)
    - January, 2005 (Box 4)
    - March, 2005 (Box 5)
    - August-September, 2005 (Box 5)
    - November, 2005 (Box 5)
    - January, 2006 (Box 5)
    - March, 2006 (Box 5)
    - May, 2006 (Box 5)
    - July, 2006 (Box 5)
    - September, 2006 (Box 5)
    - November, 2006 (Box 5)
    - January, 2007 (Box 5)
    - March, 2007 (Box 5)
    - May, 2007 (Box 5)
    - July, 2007 (Box 5)
    - December, 2007 (Box 5)
    - January, 2008 (Box 5)
    - May, 2008 (Box 5)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 34 folders
    - March-December, 2001 (Box 5)
    - January, 2002 (Box 5)
    - February-April, 2002 (Box 6)
    - June-October, 2002 (Box 6)
    - December, 2002 (Box 6)
    - January-December, 2003 (Box 6)
    - January-February, 2004 (Box 6)
  - Facility Hub/Node Directors Meeting 2004 (Box 6)
  - Facility Hub/Node Scientists Meeting 2004 (Box 6)